{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Management Information Systems",
    "Term": "Finals",
    "Title": "Group Decision Support Systems and Executive Support Systems",
    "LastModified": "3 June 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Elmer Felisilda"
    ],
    "References": [
      "11 Handout 1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What type of system helps organizational managers and executives reach a consensus during events that require their collective opinion and proposals?",
      "answer": "Group Decision Support Systems (GDSS)",
      "choices": [
        "Document-Driven DSS",
        "Model-Driven DSS",
        "Communications-Driven DSS",
        "Group Decision Support Systems (GDSS)"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS focuses on reducing pressures of conformity that results in group think?",
      "answer": "Group Problem Mitigation",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Documentation",
        "Group Problem Mitigation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS includes streamlining coordination, representation, and planning of collaboration meetings?",
      "answer": "Group Problem Mitigation",
      "choices": [
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Pre-Planning",
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
        "Group Problem Mitigation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS helps optimize group dynamics by allotting appropriate responsibilities to each collaborator?",
      "answer": "Group Problem Mitigation",
      "choices": [
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Group Problem Mitigation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS reduces the probability of the group making decisions of poor quality or high risk?",
      "answer": "Group Problem Mitigation",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency",
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Group Problem Mitigation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS provides access to rules that will aid in aiming at decisions?",
      "answer": "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
      "choices": [
        "Group Problem Mitigation",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Documentation",
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS utilizes tools and subsystems to generate useful ideas and alternatives?",
      "answer": "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Pre-Planning",
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS reduces costs for decision-making collaboration for groups?",
      "answer": "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
      "choices": [
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency",
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS allows the group to better understand problems and eliminate errors?",
      "answer": "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency",
      "choices": [
        "Documentation",
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Group Problem Mitigation",
        "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS allows members to utilize information and/or knowledge based on their areas of expertise?",
      "answer": "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency",
      "choices": [
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS streamlines group work to eliminate resistance and allows better decision consensus?",
      "answer": "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency",
      "choices": [
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which reason for using GDSS suggests that collaborators have accountability for decisions, instilling responsibility in their vote?",
      "answer": "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency",
      "choices": [
        "Documentation",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Maximization of Group Effectiveness and Efficiency"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS element addresses agendas, topics, and end-goal of the discussion?",
      "answer": "Pre-Planning",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Pre-Planning"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS element ensures ideas and communications are free-flowing without interruptions or hindrances?",
      "answer": "Collaboration Facilitation",
      "choices": [
        "Documentation",
        "Group Problem Mitigation",
        "Software",
        "Collaboration Facilitation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS element provides equal opportunity for collaborators by eliminating office politics?",
      "answer": "Evaluation Objectivity",
      "choices": [
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Evaluation Objectivity"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS element takes care of logging information from the collaboration, such as meeting minutes and voting?",
      "answer": "Documentation",
      "choices": [
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Hardware",
        "Pre-Planning",
        "Documentation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HDSS characteristic refers to equipment, computers, devices, etc.?",
      "answer": "Hardware",
      "choices": [
        "Peopleware",
        "Software",
        "Documentation",
        "Hardware"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HDSS characteristic involves not just collaborators, but also facilitators, meeting planners, hardware operators, and staff?",
      "answer": "Peopleware",
      "choices": [
        "Software",
        "Hardware",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Peopleware"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HDSS characteristic is described as programs?",
      "answer": "Software",
      "choices": [
        "Hardware",
        "Documentation",
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Software"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool allows questioning, data-gathering and investigation for planning and collaboration?",
      "answer": "Questionnaire Tools",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Questionnaire Tools"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool facilitates the creation of proposals, ideas, and solutions that help in making decisions?",
      "answer": "Electronic Brainstorming",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Documentation",
        "Electronic Brainstorming"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool may eliminate office politics by making submitted proposals and votes anonymous?",
      "answer": "Electronic Brainstorming",
      "choices": [
        "Pre-Planning",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Support of Multiple Collaboration Processes",
        "Electronic Brainstorming"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool determines the impact of the group’s decision?",
      "answer": "Stakeholder Identification",
      "choices": [
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Documentation",
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Stakeholder Identification"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool may have the capability to weigh each collaborator’s vote on a decision before finalizing it?",
      "answer": "Stakeholder Identification",
      "choices": [
        "Software",
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Stakeholder Identification"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool allows the system to reduce a particular problem into distinct interpretations?",
      "answer": "Group Dictionaries",
      "choices": [
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Software",
        "Electronic Brainstorming",
        "Group Dictionaries"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which GDSS tool uses interpretations to help decision-makers make proper decisions?",
      "answer": "Group Dictionaries",
      "choices": [
        "Questionnaire Tools",
        "Pre-Planning",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Group Dictionaries"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which DSS limitation states that it requires different types of typed, graphical, or spreadsheet input?",
      "answer": "Digitized input is required",
      "choices": [
        "Moderation is limited",
        "Documentation",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Digitized input is required"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which DSS limitation notes that the capabilities of GDSS become liabilities when multiple discussions about a decision take place?",
      "answer": "Moderation is limited",
      "choices": [
        "May require a facilitator",
        "Digitized input is required",
        "Stakeholder Identification",
        "Moderation is limited"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which DSS limitation explains that maintenance cost for a high-end facility may offset its cost-saving features?",
      "answer": "Maintenance cost may be high",
      "choices": [
        "Moderation is limited",
        "May require a facilitator",
        "Pre-Planning",
        "Maintenance cost may be high"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which DSS limitation indicates that a facilitator may be needed to help users and control the system?",
      "answer": "May require a facilitator",
      "choices": [
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Maintenance cost may be high",
        "Software",
        "May require a facilitator"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 1",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What system is tailored for executive use?",
      "answer": "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
      "choices": [
        "Decision Support System (DSS)",
        "Group Decision Support System (GDSS)",
        "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
        "Management Information System (MIS)"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What system was created to supply necessary tools for high-level decision-making?",
      "answer": "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
      "choices": [
        "Executive Role Support",
        "Data Linking",
        "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
        "Flexibility"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What system facilitates predictions, summarizes information, and provides further acquisition of data?",
      "answer": "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
      "choices": [
        "Executive Role Support",
        "Information Filtering",
        "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
        "Questionnaire Tools"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What system uses mostly external data for executive decisions?",
      "answer": "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
      "choices": [
        "Knowledge-Driven DSS",
        "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
        "Group DSS",
        "Document-Driven DSS"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What system must be flexible and easy to manipulate to accommodate different problems and situations?",
      "answer": "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
      "choices": [
        "Flexibility",
        "Executive Support Systems (ESS)",
        "Simplicity",
        "Model-Driven DSS"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role of ESS allows sifting through vast volumes of information to avoid irrelevant data?",
      "answer": "Information Filtering",
      "choices": [
        "Data Linking",
        "Evaluation Objectivity",
        "Information Filtering",
        "Questionnaire Tools"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ESS role allows executives to avoid being overwhelmed by information?",
      "answer": "Information Filtering",
      "choices": [
        "Data Linking",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Information Filtering"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role of ESS links data from various sources to provide useful information for executives?",
      "answer": "Data Linking",
      "choices": [
        "Executive Role Support",
        "Simplicity",
        "Data Linking",
        "Stakeholder Identification"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role of ESS may incorporate internet connectivity to add more system flexibility?",
      "answer": "Data Linking",
      "choices": [
        "Information Filtering",
        "Group DSS",
        "Data Linking",
        "Group Dictionaries"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role of ESS supports interpersonal, informational, and decisional roles of executives?",
      "answer": "Executive Role Support",
      "choices": [
        "Group Problem Mitigation",
        "Executive Role Support",
        "Flexibility",
        "Communication-Driven DSS"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What benefit of ESS facilitates timely data delivery through filtering, tracking, and processing?",
      "answer": "Informational Processing",
      "choices": [
        "Documentation",
        "Information Filtering",
        "Informational Processing",
        "Questionnaire Tools"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What benefit of ESS helps senior managers produce relevant information for quick decisions?",
      "answer": "Informational Processing",
      "choices": [
        "Flexibility",
        "Simplicity",
        "Informational Processing",
        "Executive Role Support"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What benefit of ESS allows executives to use the system without in-depth computer experience?",
      "answer": "Simplicity",
      "choices": [
        "Simplicity",
        "Executive Role Support",
        "Computer Skill Requirement",
        "Group DSS"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What benefit of ESS helps executives easily navigate the system?",
      "answer": "Simplicity",
      "choices": [
        "Informational Processing",
        "Simplicity",
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Pre-Planning"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What benefit of ESS allows integration with other systems due to fewer layers of management?",
      "answer": "Flexibility",
      "choices": [
        "Collaboration Facilitation",
        "Group DSS",
        "Flexibility",
        "Evaluation Objectivity"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What disadvantage of ESS assumes executives know how to operate computers?",
      "answer": "Computer Skill Requirement",
      "choices": [
        "Simplicity",
        "Computer Skill Requirement",
        "Long Processing Time",
        "Stakeholder Identification"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What disadvantage of ESS may delay results due to volume of data being processed?",
      "answer": "Long Processing Time",
      "choices": [
        "Documentation",
        "Long Processing Time",
        "Group Problem Mitigation",
        "Collaboration Facilitation"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What disadvantage of ESS is caused by insufficient summarized information from specific data?",
      "answer": "Limitations on Summarized Information",
      "choices": [
        "Group Dictionaries",
        "Difficulty in Quantifying Benefits",
        "Limitations on Summarized Information",
        "Computer Skill Requirement"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What disadvantage of ESS makes it hard to justify decisions due to summarizing of data?",
      "answer": "Difficulty in Quantifying Benefits",
      "choices": [
        "Difficulty in Quantifying Benefits",
        "Simplicity",
        "Executive Role Support",
        "Data Linking"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "What disadvantage of ESS stems from inaccurate or incorrect data due to external sources?",
      "answer": "Difficulty in Maintaining Database Integrity",
      "choices": [
        "Informational Processing",
        "Flexibility",
        "Documentation",
        "Difficulty in Maintaining Database Integrity"
      ],
      "reference": "11 Handout 1 Part 2",
      "term": "Finals"
    }
  ]
}